[
  {
    "question": "A tree with soft bark:",
    "answer": "Willow"
  },
  {
    "question": "ALF is a phase?",
    "answer": "Dark"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what height from ground level are the main photosynthesizing parts of plants located?",
    "answer": "In the tree canopy"
  },
  {
    "question": "From the fruit of which plant is cider made?",
    "answer": "Apple"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which grain is the traditional Mexican drink 'horchata' made?",
    "answer": "Rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which plant are dietary supplements made to improve heart function?",
    "answer": "Ginkgo biloba"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which plant is fabric made?",
    "answer": "Nettle"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which plant is the Panama hat made?",
    "answer": "Palm"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which plant is the traditional Japanese drink matcha made?",
    "answer": "Camellia sinensis"
  },
  {
    "question": "How are fertilizers applied to bonsai?",
    "answer": "Root method"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do ants help plants?",
    "answer": "eliminate pests"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do ferns reproduce?",
    "answer": "Spores"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do fungi obtain their nutrition?",
    "answer": "Osmotrophy"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do lichens spread?",
    "answer": "By spores"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do mosses reproduce in the presence of water?",
    "answer": "Spores"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do mosses spread in the ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Carried by the wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do mosses survive drought?",
    "answer": "Anabiosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do plants protect themselves from being eaten by insects?",
    "answer": "Toxins"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do plants spread their scent?",
    "answer": "volatile compounds"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is prickly pear used?",
    "answer": "Food"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does it take to grow a bonsai?",
    "answer": "Years"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many chromosomes do most ferns have?",
    "answer": "1280"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of plants are pollinated by bees?",
    "answer": "About 300,000"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of prickly pear cactus are there?",
    "answer": "200"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of echinacea are used in medicine?",
    "answer": "Three"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of plants are pollinated by flies?",
    "answer": "Thousands"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years have ferns existed on Earth?",
    "answer": "350 million"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what form do ferns deposit their spores?",
    "answer": "Sorus"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which century were bryophytes first classified?",
    "answer": "17th"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country does the Dragon's Blood Tree grow?",
    "answer": "Yemen"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which geological period did the first ferns appear?",
    "answer": "Devonian"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which part of the plant is callus formed?",
    "answer": "On the stems"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which places do rare species of orchids inhabit?",
    "answer": "Tropical rainforests"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which region do rare plants on the brink of extinction live?",
    "answer": "South America"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which region does the breadfruit tree grow?",
    "answer": "tropics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name a rare cactus of Central America.",
    "answer": "Echinocactus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the plant that got its name from an ancient Greek word meaning 'to heal'.",
    "answer": "Marshmallow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the plant with giant leaves reaching up to 3 meters.",
    "answer": "Rafflesia"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what mycelium does the tinder fungus grow?",
    "answer": "Woody"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lophophora cactus is known for its?",
    "answer": "Psychoactive properties"
  },
  {
    "question": "The decline of which plants led to the spread of ferns?",
    "answer": "Conifers"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which class do mosses belong?",
    "answer": "Bryophytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which class of plants do Venus flytraps belong?",
    "answer": "Carnivorous plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which division of plants do ferns belong?",
    "answer": "Polypodiopsida"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which group of plants do the Isoetaceae belong?",
    "answer": "Isoetaceae"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which group of substances does chlorophyll, which catalyzes the process of photosynthesis, belong?",
    "answer": "Pigments"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under what conditions can mosses enter a state of anabiosis?",
    "answer": "Dry conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Up to what age can baobabs live?",
    "answer": "2000 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "What acids do lichens contain?",
    "answer": "Lichen acids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What adaptations does a cactus have?",
    "answer": "water retention"
  },
  {
    "question": "What advantage do ferns have when reproducing by spores?",
    "answer": "Easily spread"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ancient name is given to ferns for their beauty?",
    "answer": "Green gifts"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are bonsai pots called in Japan?",
    "answer": "Bonsai-bachi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are flowering plants called?",
    "answer": "Angiosperms"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are mosses capable of doing?",
    "answer": "Retain water"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are phytoncides?",
    "answer": "Biologically active substances of plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are plants adapted to living on rocks called?",
    "answer": "Lithophytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are plants called that are able to adapt to arid conditions?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are plants that store water called?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the areas of tissue where cell growth occurs called?",
    "answer": "Meristems"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the habitats of mosses?",
    "answer": "Terrestrial"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the mushrooms that grow on wood called?",
    "answer": "Xylophytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the organelles that store starch called?",
    "answer": "Amyloplasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the organs of a plant that produce spores called?",
    "answer": "Sporangia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the specialized roots called that support stems in swampy conditions?",
    "answer": "Aerial roots"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the sporangia of ferns covered with?",
    "answer": "Indusium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the structures of plants called that secrete a sticky substance to catch insects?",
    "answer": "Glandules"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the structures on the underside of a fern leaf called?",
    "answer": "Sori"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the vessels for transpiration called?",
    "answer": "Xylem"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can be used for the genetic transformation of plants?",
    "answer": "Plasmids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characteristic feature do ferns have?",
    "answer": "Fronds unroll"
  },
  {
    "question": "What chemicals do plants release for protection?",
    "answer": "Toxic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What compound is the end product of glycolysis?",
    "answer": "Pyruvate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What conditions are necessary for successful in vitro cloning?",
    "answer": "Sterility"
  },
  {
    "question": "What determines the color of lichens?",
    "answer": "The type of algae"
  },
  {
    "question": "What diseases can affect bonsai?",
    "answer": "Fungal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do cacti do at night to reduce water loss?",
    "answer": "Close their stomata"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do fern spores develop into?",
    "answer": "Prothallus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do molecular biologists do?",
    "answer": "DNA analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do plants absorb during the light phase of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Light energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a plant receive from a pollinator?",
    "answer": "Fruit"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does genomics study?",
    "answer": "Study of genomes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'gametophyte' mean?",
    "answer": "Reproductive phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "What flower is called 'Kadupul'?",
    "answer": "Epiphyllum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function do the fruiting bodies of fungi serve?",
    "answer": "Reproduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does a lichen perform?",
    "answer": "Bioindicator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens during glycolysis?",
    "answer": "breakdown of glucose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens in the light phase of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Production of ATP"
  },
  {
    "question": "What illusory name does the Ranona orchid have?",
    "answer": "Mouse flower"
  },
  {
    "question": "What important role do mosses play in the ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Retain moisture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is CRISPR used for?",
    "answer": "Genome editing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is PCR used for?",
    "answer": "Gene analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an important ecosystem role of mosses?",
    "answer": "Soil formation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is aneuploidy?",
    "answer": "Abnormal number of chromosomes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is another name for the eucalyptus tree?",
    "answer": "Gum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is called 'Siberian ginseng'?",
    "answer": "Eleutherococcus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is contained in a cherry pit?",
    "answer": "Seed"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is genetic transformation?",
    "answer": "Change in DNA"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is one of the smallest flowering plants?",
    "answer": "Wolffia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is teak wood used for?",
    "answer": "Shipbuilding"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average lifespan of most fern species?",
    "answer": "Up to 100 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the film covering the spores of ferns called?",
    "answer": "Indusium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the final product of metabolism?",
    "answer": "ATP"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of wire on a bonsai?",
    "answer": "Shaping the trunk"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the inner part of the tree bark called?",
    "answer": "Phloem"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the life cycle of a fern called?",
    "answer": "Alternation of generations"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the life cycle period of perennial plants?",
    "answer": "More than a year"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main part of the fern gametophyte?",
    "answer": "Prothallus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main product of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Glucose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main source of water for cacti?",
    "answer": "Dew"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the modified stem that forms tubers called?",
    "answer": "Tuber"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for a bonsai with multiple roots exposed above the soil surface?",
    "answer": "Neagari"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a low-growing plant with small flowers?",
    "answer": "Alpine violet"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a plant with floating leaves?",
    "answer": "Hydrophyte"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a popular bonsai style?",
    "answer": "Moyogi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of one of the largest species of tree ferns?",
    "answer": "Cyathea"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Japanese knife used for trimming roots and branches?",
    "answer": "Kiri"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the cactus often used to make beverages?",
    "answer": "Peyote"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the carnivorous plant that catches insects?",
    "answer": "Sundew"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the dead wood element on a bonsai?",
    "answer": "Jin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the dinosaur tree?",
    "answer": "Wollemi"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the flower known as 'ivan-da-marya'?",
    "answer": "Melampyrum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fruit produced by the pomegranate tree?",
    "answer": "Arils"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fruit with soft flesh and spiky skin?",
    "answer": "Durian"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the genetic analysis method?",
    "answer": "DNA sequencing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the giant tree that grows in Africa?",
    "answer": "Baobab"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest living fern?",
    "answer": "Cyatheales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest species of fern?",
    "answer": "Cibotium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the largest tree in Madagascar?",
    "answer": "Baobab"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the miniature bonsai tree?",
    "answer": "Bonsai"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the mushroom with poisonous spores?",
    "answer": "Death cap"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the next-generation DNA sequencing technology?",
    "answer": "NGS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the plant that blooms only once in its lifetime?",
    "answer": "Agave"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the plant that is often mistaken for moss?",
    "answer": "Riccia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the plant that produces peanuts?",
    "answer": "Peanut"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the plant with beautiful flowers native to Bulgaria?",
    "answer": "Cuckoo flower"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the plant with long leaves and yellow flowers?",
    "answer": "Yellow Iris"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare Mexican moss?",
    "answer": "Selaginella lepidophylla"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare exotic flower that can weigh up to 11 kilograms?",
    "answer": "Rafflesia Arnoldii"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare fern?",
    "answer": "Marsilea quadrifolia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare mushroom with bleeding droplets?",
    "answer": "Hydnellum peckii"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare plant with bright yellow flowers that grows in South Africa?",
    "answer": "Cape Daisy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare shrub with blue fruits that grows in Australia?",
    "answer": "Pestrusha"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare species of cedar that grows in Morocco?",
    "answer": "Atlas cedar"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare tree fern?",
    "answer": "Cyathea crinita"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the rare tree that blooms once every 40 years?",
    "answer": "Talipot palm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the tree with red bark?",
    "answer": "Sequoia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the unique tree with fire-resistant bark that grows in California?",
    "answer": "Sequoiadendron"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the white flowering plant in the Andes?",
    "answer": "Espeletia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the native country of the agave plant?",
    "answer": "Mexico"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nature of lichens?",
    "answer": "Symbiotic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the oldest living tree in the world?",
    "answer": "Methuselah"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the oldest type of fern?",
    "answer": "Ophioglossum vulgatum"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the part of the photosynthetic apparatus called that conducts only the light phase?",
    "answer": "Photosystem"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the plant called that is scientifically referred to as 'Acanthaceae'?",
    "answer": "Acanthus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the plant known as 'the tree of heaven'?",
    "answer": "Ailanthus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process called in which a plant absorbs carbon dioxide?",
    "answer": "Photosynthesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of achieving homozygosity called?",
    "answer": "Pure line"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of converting sucrose called?",
    "answer": "Hydrolysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of electron transfer called?",
    "answer": "Electron transport chain"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of forming organic substances from CO2 in the dark phase called?",
    "answer": "Calvin Cycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of interaction between plants and insects called?",
    "answer": "Pollination"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of lengthening called?",
    "answer": "Elongation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of moss reproduction called?",
    "answer": "Spore formation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of organic synthesis in plants called?",
    "answer": "Photosynthesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of photosynthesis in cacti called?",
    "answer": "Photosynthesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the protective layer on succulents called?",
    "answer": "Epidermis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of trimming bonsai roots?",
    "answer": "Restricting growth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the rare plant Amorphophallus commonly known as?",
    "answer": "Corpse flower"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the reproductive organ of ferns called?",
    "answer": "Sorus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the rhizome of a fern?",
    "answer": "Underground stem"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of lichens in the ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Bioindicator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of the gametophyte in the life cycle of mosses?",
    "answer": "Reproduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of water in photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Electron donor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the science of lichens called?",
    "answer": "Lichenology"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the science that studies ferns called?",
    "answer": "Pteridology"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the structure called that forms spores in mosses?",
    "answer": "Sporangium"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the symbiosis between ants and acacia called?",
    "answer": "Mutualism"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for additional plant nutrition using animals?",
    "answer": "Carnivory"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for an ordered set of genes?",
    "answer": "Genome"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for the dormancy period in mosses under unfavorable conditions?",
    "answer": "Anabiosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used to fertilize bonsai in the spring?",
    "answer": "nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is xylem?",
    "answer": "Plant tissue"
  },
  {
    "question": "What mechanism do sundews use to catch insects?",
    "answer": "Sticky substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method can be used to alter DNA?",
    "answer": "Genetic engineering"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method can be used to improve soil drainage for bonsai?",
    "answer": "Gravel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method do plants use to combat insects?",
    "answer": "secretion of toxins"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method do special plants use to catch and digest insects?",
    "answer": "Predation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method is used to check genetic diversity?",
    "answer": "PCR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method is used to study genes?",
    "answer": "Sequencing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method of insect protection do maples use?",
    "answer": "Phytoncides"
  },
  {
    "question": "What methods improve plant genes?",
    "answer": "Breeding and GMO"
  },
  {
    "question": "What occurs in the thylakoid membranes?",
    "answer": "Light phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "What part of the moss life cycle does the gametophyte occupy?",
    "answer": "Main"
  },
  {
    "question": "What percentage of plant species are pollinated by bees?",
    "answer": "90%"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plant is the symbol of Indonesia?",
    "answer": "Rafflesia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plant strategy prevents them from being eaten by insects?",
    "answer": "Defensive thorns"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plant symbolizes September?",
    "answer": "Aster"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plants are characteristic of the mangrove ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Mangrove trees"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plants can be cultivated in a winter garden?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plants grow in swamps?",
    "answer": "Peat mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plants grow in the tundra?",
    "answer": "Lichens"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process allows for the preservation of genetic diversity?",
    "answer": "Crossbreeding"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process allows the transfer of genes from one plant to another?",
    "answer": "Genetic engineering"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process creates genetic diversity?",
    "answer": "Mutation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process doubles DNA for analysis?",
    "answer": "PCR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process occurs in the roots?",
    "answer": "Absorption of water"
  },
  {
    "question": "What process releases water from leaves?",
    "answer": "Transpiration"
  },
  {
    "question": "What rare plant grows in the Namib Desert?",
    "answer": "Welwitschia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What rare plant inhabits the marshy areas of Russia?",
    "answer": "Bog rosemary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What rare plant is found in Alaska?",
    "answer": "Poppy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role does the mycelium perform?",
    "answer": "Absorption of substances"
  },
  {
    "question": "What shape can lichens have?",
    "answer": "Foliose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What shape do lichens usually take?",
    "answer": "Crust"
  },
  {
    "question": "What sprouts are grown from a test tube?",
    "answer": "in vitro"
  },
  {
    "question": "What structure forms the body of a lichen?",
    "answer": "Thallus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What structures do plants use to catch insects?",
    "answer": "Traps"
  },
  {
    "question": "What structures in plants facilitate gas exchange?",
    "answer": "Stomata"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance attracts insects?",
    "answer": "glucose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance do tree bark cells contain?",
    "answer": "Cellulose"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance found in the male fern is used in medicine?",
    "answer": "Filicin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance in plants can kill insects?",
    "answer": "alkaloids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substances do lichens release?",
    "answer": "Organic acids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technique allows for editing plant genes?",
    "answer": "CRISPR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What tissue do ferns need for water transport?",
    "answer": "Vascular tissue"
  },
  {
    "question": "What to do if a bonsai is sick?",
    "answer": "Treat it"
  },
  {
    "question": "What trees are characteristic of savanna ecosystems?",
    "answer": "Baobabs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What trees are used for the production of frankincense?",
    "answer": "Boswellia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What tropical plant grows in the Amazon?",
    "answer": "Hevea"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of cactus produces mescaline?",
    "answer": "Lophophora"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of coating is characteristic of desert plant leaves?",
    "answer": "Waxy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of coniferous tree has a pyramid-shaped crown?",
    "answer": "spruce"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of diet do ants have?",
    "answer": "Omnivores"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of fern tissue is used for the transport of water and minerals?",
    "answer": "Xylem"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of fruit does a peanut have?",
    "answer": "Legume"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of mushrooms grow in symbiosis with trees?",
    "answer": "Mycorrhizal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of mushrooms often grow on tree roots?",
    "answer": "mycorrhizal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of pollination is most common among plants?",
    "answer": "Anemophily"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of reproduction do mosses use in the haploid stage?",
    "answer": "Spore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of seeds does a pine tree have?",
    "answer": "Cones"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of tree is used for building ships?",
    "answer": "Oak"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of water supply is absent in mosses?",
    "answer": "Vascular system"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of wood is Africa famous for?",
    "answer": "Ebony"
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of ferns are used in medicine?",
    "answer": "Shield fern"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did bonsai appear in Japan?",
    "answer": "13th century"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are chromoplasts located?",
    "answer": "In plant cells"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are the stomata located on cacti?",
    "answer": "On the stem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can endemic plants be found?",
    "answer": "Isolated regions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can the greatest variety of plants be found?",
    "answer": "Tropical rainforest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you find rare plants that grow only on cliffs?",
    "answer": "In the Andes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you find the Lebanese cedar?",
    "answer": "Lebanon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do modern ferns originate from?",
    "answer": "Devonian period"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do succulents store moisture?",
    "answer": "In the leaves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does heather grow?",
    "answer": "In the forest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does knotweed grow?",
    "answer": "In meadows"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does membrane transport occur in plants?",
    "answer": "Vacuole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the main carbon fixation occur?",
    "answer": "Stroma of chloroplasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the rare plant Fefera grow?",
    "answer": "Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is glucose synthesized in a plant?",
    "answer": "Leaves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Chinese plant is specifically cultivated for use in tea?",
    "answer": "Chrysanthemum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which DNA analysis method allows for the detection of mutations?",
    "answer": "PCR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which DNA analysis technique is the most accurate?",
    "answer": "Sequencing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which algae is most common in freshwater?",
    "answer": "Chlorella"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancient type of fern still exists?",
    "answer": "Oligofloum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which annual plant is delicious when cooked?",
    "answer": "Fennel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aquatic plant floats on the surface?",
    "answer": "Duckweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aquatic plant is called 'water cabbage'?",
    "answer": "Pistia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which berries are known for their help with inflammations?",
    "answer": "Cranberries"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which biological reaction creates conditions for the transmission of hereditary information?",
    "answer": "Meiosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bonsai style creates the illusion of an old tree?",
    "answer": "Seizan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cacti are known for their night blooming?",
    "answer": "Epiphyllums"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cactus is known for its night-blooming flowers?",
    "answer": "Selenicereus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cellular structure is used for genetic transformation of plants?",
    "answer": "Agrobacterium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cellular structure produces saccharides?",
    "answer": "chloroplasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country is the native home of the 'Blue Fern'?",
    "answer": "New Zealand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country is the native home of the cycad?",
    "answer": "South Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cycle is initiated by carbon dioxide?",
    "answer": "Calvin Cycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ecosystem is a transitional zone between forest and steppe?",
    "answer": "Forest-steppe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element is necessary for the synthesis of chlorophyll?",
    "answer": "Iron"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element is present in the largest amount in photosynthetic pigments?",
    "answer": "Magnesium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which factor is the main one for bonsai growth?",
    "answer": "Pruning"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fern can reach a height of 20 meters?",
    "answer": "Dicksonia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ferns are used in gardening?",
    "answer": "Polypodiums"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower attracts nocturnal insects?",
    "answer": "Mirabilis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower blooms in winter?",
    "answer": "Azalea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower blooms the least often?",
    "answer": "Puya Raimondii"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower grows from a tuber?",
    "answer": "Begonia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower is called the 'flower of love'?",
    "answer": "Orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower is cultivated for obtaining essential oil?",
    "answer": "Jasmine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower is often called the 'flower of evil'?",
    "answer": "Belladonna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flowering plant from the orchid family is widely known?",
    "answer": "Phalaenopsis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flowering plant is known for its medicinal properties?",
    "answer": "Calendula"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flowers change color during blooming?",
    "answer": "Hydrangeas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit has pink skin and white flesh?",
    "answer": "Dragon fruit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is called the 'winter rose' in China?",
    "answer": "Lychee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is commonly used to make guava jam?",
    "answer": "Guava"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is known for its hairy skins?",
    "answer": "Kiwi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is known for its high content of vitamins A and E?",
    "answer": "Mango"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is used to make the traditional Japanese drink umeshu?",
    "answer": "Ume"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit tastes like an orange and grows on shrubs?",
    "answer": "Sea buckthorn"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fungi most commonly form a symbiosis with tree roots?",
    "answer": "Mycorrhizal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group of fungi are parasites?",
    "answer": "Rust fungi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herb is popular in Mediterranean cuisine?",
    "answer": "Oregano"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbaceous plant is called the 'jubilee flower'?",
    "answer": "Carnation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbaceous plant is cultivated for obtaining dye?",
    "answer": "madder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbaceous plant is used in perfumery?",
    "answer": "Lavender"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect harms the oat crop?",
    "answer": "Grasshopper"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect is used to control aphid populations in gardens?",
    "answer": "Gall midge"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect pollinates plants at night?",
    "answer": "Moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects are attracted to woodlice?",
    "answer": "Moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects are known as pollinators of the aspen tree?",
    "answer": "Aspen beetles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects devastate wheat crops?",
    "answer": "Locusts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects feed on plant roots?",
    "answer": "Root flies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects produce honeydew?",
    "answer": "Aphids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichen is an indicator of pollution?",
    "answer": "Fruticose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichen is used as a dye?",
    "answer": "Litmus lichen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichen is used as an indicator of air purity?",
    "answer": "Cetraria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens are used in medicine?",
    "answer": "Cetraria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens are used in perfumery?",
    "answer": "evernia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens can be found in Arctic regions?",
    "answer": "Reindeer lichen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens can serve as indicators of pollution?",
    "answer": "Biomonitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens contain bright red pigments?",
    "answer": "Teloschistaceae"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lichens grow on rocks and stones?",
    "answer": "Crustose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which meadow is known for its flowers?",
    "answer": "Alpine meadow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which molecule is the primary energy carrier in plants?",
    "answer": "ATP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mosses can be found in glacial areas?",
    "answer": "Polytrichum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mosses can grow in the desert?",
    "answer": "Xerophilous mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mosses can survive in high radiation conditions?",
    "answer": "Radiophilic mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mosses precede forest ecosystems?",
    "answer": "Pioneer mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mushroom is known for its glow?",
    "answer": "Honey fungus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mushrooms glow in the dark?",
    "answer": "Pholiota"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the ferns has medicinal uses?",
    "answer": "Male fern"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following plants is carnivorous?",
    "answer": "Bladderwort"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which orchid is a rare species?",
    "answer": "Phalaenopsis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which orders of insects are known as pollinators of plants?",
    "answer": "Hymenoptera"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organic compound is the starting material for plant respiration?",
    "answer": "Glucose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organisms often damage plant roots?",
    "answer": "Nematodes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organisms, besides plants, are capable of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Cyanobacteria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of a fern is called sori?",
    "answer": "Sorus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of a lichen usually consists of algae or cyanobacteria?",
    "answer": "Photobiont"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of moss cells is involved in photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Chloroplasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the fern contains the spore-bearing organs?",
    "answer": "Leaf"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the fern protects the spores?",
    "answer": "Sporangia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the tree is responsible for growth?",
    "answer": "Cambium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the tree transports water from the roots to the leaves?",
    "answer": "Xylem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which phase of photosynthesis synthesizes ATP?",
    "answer": "Light-dependent"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant attracts attention with its silvery leaves?",
    "answer": "Wormwood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant attracts many insects with its color?",
    "answer": "Gypsophila"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant belongs to the class of bryophytes?",
    "answer": "Fontinalis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant blooms all year round?",
    "answer": "Geranium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant blooms in spring and has pink flowers?",
    "answer": "Phlox"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant blooms in winter?",
    "answer": "Christmas cactus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant blooms on rocky slopes?",
    "answer": "Sedum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant can be planted in a rock garden?",
    "answer": "Sempervivum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant can be used to decorate a pond?",
    "answer": "Water iris"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant can bloom underwater?",
    "answer": "Lotus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant can change color depending on the soil's acidity?",
    "answer": "Hydrangea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant can grow at the bottom of water bodies?",
    "answer": "Pondweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant cells are capable of transforming into meristematic cells?",
    "answer": "cambium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant cells regulate gas exchange and transpiration?",
    "answer": "Guard cells"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant contains a large amount of iron?",
    "answer": "Nettle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant forms large floating leaves?",
    "answer": "Victoria amazonica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant from the amaranth family produces flower umbels and has small red flowers?",
    "answer": "Amaranth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant from the cactus family is used to create living fences and has long needle-like spines?",
    "answer": "Prickly Pear (Opuntia)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant grows in soil with high acidity?",
    "answer": "Azalea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has a diuretic effect?",
    "answer": "Bearberry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has a very fine structure and is often found in still waters?",
    "answer": "Riccia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has antimicrobial properties?",
    "answer": "Thymus vulgaris"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has edible seeds called 'chilim'?",
    "answer": "Water caltrop"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has flowers underwater?",
    "answer": "Water milfoil"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has giant aerial bulbs?",
    "answer": "Longin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has orange flowers and is often used in antispasmodic collections?",
    "answer": "Calendula"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has pods with spices?",
    "answer": "Tamarind"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has red flowers and prefers shade?",
    "answer": "Begonia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has the ability to 'breathe' through its roots?",
    "answer": "Pandanus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has underwater flowers and leaves floating on the water surface?",
    "answer": "Water lily"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant has underwater stems?",
    "answer": "Pondweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant helps with colds?",
    "answer": "Fireweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant helps with gastritis and stomach ulcers?",
    "answer": "Angelica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant helps with stomach ulcers?",
    "answer": "Plantain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is a natural antiseptic?",
    "answer": "Celandine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is a natural tonic?",
    "answer": "Ginseng"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is a popular honey plant?",
    "answer": "Alfalfa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is a symbol of the Mediterranean?",
    "answer": "Olive tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is actively used in biotechnology for creating new species?",
    "answer": "Fern"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is adapted to live both in water and on land?",
    "answer": "Cattail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is also known as 'Adam's head'?",
    "answer": "Gentian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is also known as autumn gold?",
    "answer": "Goldenrod"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is an epiphyte and grows on trees?",
    "answer": "orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is an important source of food and medicine in the tropics?",
    "answer": "Bamboo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'Bogorodskaya grass'?",
    "answer": "Thyme"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'female ginseng'?",
    "answer": "Dong Quai"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'gvozdika travyanka'?",
    "answer": "Dianthus deltoides"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'living stones'?",
    "answer": "Lithops"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'water star'?",
    "answer": "Alisma"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'yellow gold' of Indonesia?",
    "answer": "Zingiber"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called 'частуха'?",
    "answer": "Alisma plantago-aquatica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called a 'living fossil'?",
    "answer": "Ginkgo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called a natural filter?",
    "answer": "Pondweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'Chinese globe chrysanthemum'?",
    "answer": "Celosia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'Corpse Flower'?",
    "answer": "Rafflesia Arnoldii"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'camel stick'?",
    "answer": "Stapelia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'green hydra'?",
    "answer": "Chara"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'king of herbs' due to its beneficial properties?",
    "answer": "Ginseng"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is called the 'rattan palm'?",
    "answer": "rattan palm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is characterized by small white flowers?",
    "answer": "Baby's breath"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is commonly found in meadows?",
    "answer": "Dactylis glomerata"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is cultivated in ornamental ponds?",
    "answer": "Water lily"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is endemic to Madagascar?",
    "answer": "Triumphant palm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is famous for its bright leaves?",
    "answer": "Coleus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is famous for its eccentric carnivorous flowers?",
    "answer": "Nepenthes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is famous for its flowers with bright orange-red hues?",
    "answer": "Heliacanthus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is found in the Far Eastern taiga?",
    "answer": "Aralia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is grown in water bodies?",
    "answer": "Water lily"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is highly valued for its blue flowers?",
    "answer": "Bellflower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known as the 'winter guest'?",
    "answer": "Cyclamen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its aerial roots and is found in India and other parts of Asia?",
    "answer": "Banyan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its bright blue color and grows in the north of Kamchatka?",
    "answer": "Kamchatka Rhododendron"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its bright flowers and numerous species?",
    "answer": "Orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its decorative flowers in spring?",
    "answer": "Azalea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its fragrant flowers?",
    "answer": "Gardenia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its giant leaves?",
    "answer": "Victoria amazonica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its long, intertwining stems?",
    "answer": "Climbing bean"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its unique taste and grows everywhere?",
    "answer": "Papaya"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its unusual petal structure?",
    "answer": "Orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its unusual scent?",
    "answer": "Titan arum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is known for its waterproof leaves?",
    "answer": "Lotus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is listed in the European Red Book?",
    "answer": "Fritillaria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is listed in the Red Book of Russia?",
    "answer": "Nut-bearing lotus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is most commonly found in the tropics?",
    "answer": "Filifolium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is most commonly used for creating a bioplateau?",
    "answer": "Pistia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is named after a U.S. President?",
    "answer": "Clivia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is obtained from the bark of a tree and used for soap?",
    "answer": "Soapwort"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often added to black tea?",
    "answer": "Bergamot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often associated with winter?",
    "answer": "Poinsettia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often called 'rapunzel'?",
    "answer": "Rampion bellflower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often called 'sea grape'?",
    "answer": "Coccoloba"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often grown for decorative purposes?",
    "answer": "Clematis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often grown in alpine flower beds?",
    "answer": "Edelweiss"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often grown in rock gardens?",
    "answer": "Sedum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often mistaken for a water lily?",
    "answer": "Lotus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often planted along roads?",
    "answer": "Daylily"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often planted in rock gardens?",
    "answer": "Alpine pink"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often used for creating green walls?",
    "answer": "Ivy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often used for floral arrangements?",
    "answer": "Gypsophila"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often used for rock gardens?",
    "answer": "Sedum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often used for topiaries?",
    "answer": "Boxwood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is often used in floral arrangements?",
    "answer": "Statice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is particularly sensitive to overwatering?",
    "answer": "Cactus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is popular among carnivorous plants?",
    "answer": "Nepenthes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is rarely grown in northern latitudes?",
    "answer": "Watermelon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is referred to as a tub plant?",
    "answer": "Laurel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is the most popular among shade lovers?",
    "answer": "Fern"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is typical for the steppe?",
    "answer": "Feather grass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is underwater and twines?",
    "answer": "Chara"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used as a sweetener?",
    "answer": "Stevia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used for arranging decorative bouquets?",
    "answer": "Asparagus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used for the production of viscose?",
    "answer": "Bamboo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used in medicine for treating respiratory tract?",
    "answer": "Plantain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used to fight colds?",
    "answer": "Honeysuckle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used to make spices?",
    "answer": "Sage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is used to relieve stress?",
    "answer": "Motherwort"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is well-suited for hedges?",
    "answer": "Yew"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant is widely known for its antibacterial properties?",
    "answer": "Echinacea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant needs to be pruned to create a crown shape?",
    "answer": "Topiary"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant often becomes an epiphyte in the tropics?",
    "answer": "Orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant organ performs transpiration?",
    "answer": "Leaves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant prefers partial shade?",
    "answer": "Fern"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant prefers shallow water?",
    "answer": "Sweet flag"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant produces a fruit with sweet flesh and a strong odor?",
    "answer": "durian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant produces goji berries?",
    "answer": "Lycium barbarum"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant resembles a netting?",
    "answer": "Fritillaria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant secretes milky sap?",
    "answer": "dandelion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant stimulates appetite?",
    "answer": "Pechernitsa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant symbolizes immortality?",
    "answer": "Aloe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant tissue contributes to its strength?",
    "answer": "Sclerenchyma"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant was used to produce blue dye?",
    "answer": "Indigofera"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are adapted to live in water?",
    "answer": "Aquatic plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are anchored to the bottom of water bodies?",
    "answer": "Rhizomatous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are capable of fixing nitrogen from the air?",
    "answer": "Legumes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are capable of surviving in salty water?",
    "answer": "Mangroves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are commonly found in coastal areas?",
    "answer": "Mangroves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are known for their ability to regenerate tissues?",
    "answer": "multicolored plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are known for their ability to trap insects?",
    "answer": "Venus flytraps"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are not recommended for beginners in bonsai?",
    "answer": "Conifers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are often grown for decorating rock gardens?",
    "answer": "Alpine asters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are often used for roadside landscaping?",
    "answer": "jasmine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are suitable for rock gardens?",
    "answer": "Aralias"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are used for chlorophyll enrichment?",
    "answer": "Microalgae"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are used in laboratory experiments?",
    "answer": "Arabidopsis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants attract ants for protection against other insects?",
    "answer": "Acacias"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants attract flies?",
    "answer": "Holly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants can survive in swamps?",
    "answer": "Mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants dominate in arid zones?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants dominated in the Paleozoic era?",
    "answer": "Ferns"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants feed on insects to obtain nitrogen?",
    "answer": "Venus flytrap"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants grow the slowest?",
    "answer": "Trees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants have the ability to retain water and survive in drought conditions?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants play a key role in the decomposition of organic matter in bogs?",
    "answer": "Mosses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants prefer acidic soil?",
    "answer": "Azaleas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants prefer frequent watering?",
    "answer": "Hydrangea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants produce a sticky liquid to catch insects?",
    "answer": "Carnivorous plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants produce sticky sap to catch insects?",
    "answer": "Carnivorous plants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants protect themselves with poisonous substances?",
    "answer": "Nettle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants take root in sand dunes?",
    "answer": "Rhizomatous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pollinators can help a bonsai in blooming?",
    "answer": "Bees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primary bonsai style imitates the slant of trees under the influence of wind?",
    "answer": "Shakan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which process produces ATP in the light phase of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Photolysis of water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protein binds to DNA?",
    "answer": "Histone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which rare orchid is called the 'Ghost Flower'?",
    "answer": "Dendrophylax Orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which rare plant is known by the name 'Konorduli'?",
    "answer": "Tecoma staffa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which rare plant is used in Asian medicine and is famous for its black roots?",
    "answer": "Black Korean ginseng"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which rare plant of Arabia contains giant seeds?",
    "answer": "Dragon's Blood Pine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which shrub has red berries?",
    "answer": "Elderberry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which shrub produces blueberries?",
    "answer": "Blueberry bush"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which shrub produces white berries?",
    "answer": "Snowberry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structure in mosses is involved in photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Protonema"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structure in mosses is multicellular?",
    "answer": "Apical meristem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structure of a fungus is responsible for releasing spores?",
    "answer": "Sporangium"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structure of a lichen serves for attachment to the substrate?",
    "answer": "Rhizoids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structures in a plant perform the function of gas exchange?",
    "answer": "Stomata"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structures perform the functions of roots?",
    "answer": "rhizome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which succulents are popular in medicine?",
    "answer": "aloe vera"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technique uses enzymes in cloning?",
    "answer": "PCR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tissue in leaves is responsible for gas exchange?",
    "answer": "Mesophyll"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree has antibacterial properties?",
    "answer": "Larch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree has gray leaves?",
    "answer": "Olive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree has white wood?",
    "answer": "Poplar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree is a symbol of independence and freedom in the USA?",
    "answer": "Oak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree is most commonly used for bonsai?",
    "answer": "Ficus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree is often used in medicine?",
    "answer": "Birch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree is often used in perfumery?",
    "answer": "Sandalwood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree is one of the longest-living?",
    "answer": "Sequoia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree often grows in swamps?",
    "answer": "Alder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant has giant leaves?",
    "answer": "Victoria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant has the largest leaves?",
    "answer": "Rafflesia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is famous for its bright red flowers and is used in perfumery?",
    "answer": "Ylang-ylang"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is grown for its beautiful flowers and fragrant leaves?",
    "answer": "Gardenia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is known as a 'carnivorous plant'?",
    "answer": "Nepenthes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is known as the king of orchids?",
    "answer": "Vanda"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is known for its ability to retain water?",
    "answer": "Alocasia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is renowned for its antibacterial properties and is used in traditional medicine?",
    "answer": "Neem"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant is used in weaving?",
    "answer": "Rattan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant produces nutmeg?",
    "answer": "Nutmeg tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical plant provides aromatic spices?",
    "answer": "Cinnamon tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical tree can grow taller than 30 meters?",
    "answer": "Baobab"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tropical vine has yellow, red, and green fruits?",
    "answer": "Passionflower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of orchid is popular due to its easy care?",
    "answer": "Phalaenopsis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of pea is an annual plant?",
    "answer": "Edible"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who discovered the structure of DNA?",
    "answer": "Watson and Crick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who helps the lichen synthesize organic substances?",
    "answer": "Algae"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are mosses important for ecosystems?",
    "answer": "Soil formation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are mushrooms beneficial for the forest?",
    "answer": "Decompose organic matter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can lichens grow on rocks?",
    "answer": "They secrete acids"
  }
]